So the first situation we're going to look at is addiction.
所以我们要研究的第一种情况是成瘾。
Addiction.
瘾。
Somebody is doing something too much.
有人做的太多了。
Well if you have a good friend who's doing something too much you might want to help them.
好吧，如果你有一个做得太多的好朋友，你可能想帮助他们。
You may need to mention to your friend that there hey there is a problem.
您可能需要向您的朋友提及，嘿，有问题。
Maybe this is not healthy for you.
也许这对你不健康。
Well let's focus on video games.
好吧，让我们专注于视频游戏。
Not to say that video games are bad.
并不是说电子游戏不好。
I like video games.
我喜欢电子游戏。
But sometimes people can get addicted addicted to video games and if they get addicted to video games.
但有时人们会沉迷于电子游戏，如果他们沉迷于电子游戏。
Well what happens.
那么会发生什么。
Maybe other things in that person's life may be out of balance right.
也许那个人生活中的其他事情可能会失去平衡。
So you think your friend is spending too much time playing video games.
所以你认为你的朋友花太多时间玩电子游戏。
How can you bring up mentioned the topic and make it softer.
你怎么能提到这个话题并让它变得更柔和。
This means we don't want to be too direct because if we're too direct and we say something like Hey
这意味着我们不想太直接，因为如果我们太直接了，我们会说嘿
friend you have a problem what do people do when you say that to them.
朋友，你有一个问题，当你对他们这么说时，人们会怎么做。
Well they become defensive.
好吧，他们变得防守。
They might say oh no I don't.
他们可能会说哦，不，我没有。
I don't talk about her and not want to talk to you if you criticize people too directly.
如果你太直接地批评人，我不谈论她，也不想和你说话。
Usually they become defensive and they don't want to listen to what you're saying.
通常他们会变得防守，他们不想听你在说什么。
So how can we say that we can bring up the topic of hey you have this problem without being too straight.
那么我们怎么能说我们可以提出嘿你有这个问题的话题而不会太直截了当。
How can we do that.
我们怎么能这样做。
Well there's one very common expression that we can use to express the idea of addiction and we can
嗯，我们可以用一种非常常见的表达方式来表达成瘾的概念，我们可以
use it for many other situations too.
也可以在许多其他情况下使用它。
And that is that is out of hand now out of hand.
那就是现在已经失控了。
It's sort of like saying out of control not in control.
这有点像说失控而不是失控。
And we'll talk about other situations in which we can use it.
我们将讨论可以使用它的其他情况。
But let's just focus on this situation first.
但是，让我们首先关注这种情况。
OK let's let's say it like this.
好吧，让我们这样说吧。
Hey Tom can I can I talk to you for a second.
嘿，汤姆，我可以和你谈谈吗？
Yeah yeah.
是啊。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
So we might say listen listen.
所以我们可以说听听。
It's a way to begin a serious topic I think.
我认为这是开始一个严肃话题的一种方式。
I think your gaming habit is getting a bit.
我认为你的游戏习惯有点。
Remember we use a bit when we want to make things softer.
请记住，当我们想让事情变得更柔软时，我们会使用一点。
Right.
正确的。
So it's always useful a bit out of hand.
所以它总是有点失控。
And this is the expression that we're learning how to use.
这是我们正在学习如何使用的表达方式。
Well that's a big difference between saying you have a problem and I think you're gaming habit is getting
嗯，说你有问题和我认为你正在养成游戏习惯之间有很大的不同
a bit out of hand.
有点失控。
This is so soft that Tom is likely to be more receptive and listen to what you're saying.
这太软了，汤姆可能更容易接受并倾听你在说什么。
Do you think so.
你觉得是吗。
Yeah I know but I can't stop.
是的，我知道，但我不能停下来。
Well then we can talk about solutions.
那么我们可以谈谈解决方案。
So a bit out of hand.
所以有点失控。
I do want to get into using out of hand in more situations how else it can be used but very quickly
我确实想在更多情况下失控地使用它，但它可以如何使用但非常快
we could also say I think your gaming habit is getting a bit out of hand and we could add.
我们也可以说我认为您的游戏习惯有点失控，我们可以补充。
And you really need to draw the line somewhere.
你真的需要在某处划清界限。
OK.
好的。
So this one to draw the line somewhere is to create a limit any anytime you want to talk about giving
所以这个在某处划清界限是在你想谈论给予的任何时候创造一个限制
yourself a limit or giving others a limit.
给自己一个限制或给别人一个限制。
We might say draw the line.
我们可以说划清界限。
I'm going to draw the line with you.
我要和你划清界限。
You can only watch TV for an hour a day maybe a mother will say that to her son.
你每天只能看一个小时的电视，也许母亲会对她的儿子这么说。
I'm really going to have to draw the line.
我真的要划清界限。
Well you could say it for yourself and you really need to draw the line somewhere.
好吧，您可以自己说，您确实需要在某个地方划清界限。
That means you need to create a limit for yourself about how much you're going to play.
这意味着您需要为自己设定一个限制你要去玩。
Right.
正确的。
An hour a day two hours a day and then stop.
每天一小时，每天两小时，然后停下来。
Draw the line somewhere.
在某处画线。
All right.
好的。
Let's go back to out of hand and other places where we can use it to express a situation that is no
让我们回到失控和其他我们可以用它来表达一种情况的地方
longer in control.
控制时间更长。
Have you ever seen on the news crowd of people we could say even a mob of people smashing windows in
你有没有在新闻中看到一群人，我们甚至可以说是一群人在砸窗户
the streets and flipping over cars.
街道和翻车。
Sometimes it's after a sports match or some other reason.
有时是在体育比赛或其他原因之后。
Doesn't matter.
没关系。
Well in this case maybe the police no longer have control over the situation.
那么在这种情况下，也许警察不再控制局势。
Maybe they did.
也许他们做到了。
They had control they had control and then it reached a point where the police no longer have control.
他们控制了他们控制了，然后它达到了警察不再控制的地步。
So we can say the mob the mob the mob started to get out of hand out of hand.
所以我们可以说暴民暴民开始失控。
So you can use it for your self your habits what you do if you do something too much.
因此，如果您做太多事情，您可以将其用于您自己的习惯。
When you lose control of that thing.
当你失去对那件事的控制时。
But it can also be used to describe something out there in the world with people.
但它也可以用来描述世界上与人在一起的事物。
And for example maybe the police have control or should have control but now they don't.
例如，也许警察有控制权或应该有控制权，但现在他们没有。
And so it's out of hand it's out of hand.
所以它失控了。
OK.
好的。
So it's a very very useful and it can be used in all kinds of situations.
所以它非常有用，可以在各种情况下使用。
Let's go on and look at another situation and another very useful expression we can use in that situation.
让我们继续看看另一种情况，以及我们可以在这种情况下使用的另一种非常有用的表达方式。